Skill Out
========ED=======
Teacher's Lounge
Phew...
Oh, Tessou-sensei.
おや　鉄装先生
You're working hard even on summer vacation.
夏休みだと言うのに　ご苦労さんですね
Yes.
え　終わってない仕事がありまして
There's lots of unfinished work.
You look busy.
お忙しいそうですな
Yes...
はい
Oh my, it's so late now!
もうこんな時間
You have work over there, too?
今日はあちらのお仕事も
そうなんですよ
That's right.
Okay, I'm leaving.
じゃ　私がこれで
Take care!
お気をつけて
Ouch...
痛い
On no, I don't have the time for this!
あ　こんな事してる場合じゃ
Really...
本当に
Take care please...
お気をつけて
Oh, this is bad!
やばい
Wait up!
待って
I'm totally late!
完璧に遅刻だ
響き合う願いが今覚醒めてく
脑海中回响着的愿望现已苏醒
譲れない未来のために
为了绝不可相让的未来
巡り逢う運命を超えたその先に
只因在超越命运的前方
この想い輝くから
这份思念正闪耀着光芒
ここじゃない未来に
在那并非归属的未来
想い託してみては
寄存着这份思念
強さの本当の意味を
继续寻找着那
搜し続けてた
强大的真正意义
ありのままの痛みを
将各种痛苦
受け入れるその意味を
全部承受的意义
明日へ走り続ける君に知った
是奔向明天的你告诉了我
巡りゆく景色が今流れてく
那眼前的景色现已过去
手繰り寄せた世界の先
那紧牵着双手的世界的前方
降り注ぐシグナルを躰で感じて
身体已感觉到其中所倾注的信号
解き放つ今全てを
此刻解放所有一切
Just truth in my heart
いつだって迷わないよ
无论何时都不应迷茫
消せない想いがあるから
因为有着无法磨灭的思念
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
直视那已经揭开的真相
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな絆信じて
请相信这份羁绊
I'm late!
遅くなりました
You're really late.
盛大に遅刻してくれるじゃん
I-I'm sorry.
す　すみません
Students get restless during summer vacation.
夏休みは学生が浮付く
Sometimes, when the task of maintaining order gets too much for Judgement, we get called up to help.
<Jugement>
风纪委员だけじゃ風紀の維持が難しいから
こうやってこちらが出張ってるってのに
So, why are you the one who seems so restless?
お前が浮付いて　どうするじゃん
I-I'm sorry...
す　すみません
Geez...
たっく
Yes, it's Yomikawa.
はい　黄泉川
A robbery?!
強盗
Understood.
了解
Redeem yourself by working hard, all right?
失敗は仕事で取り返せ　いいなぁ
Yes!
はい
Y-Yomikawa-sensei...!
よ　黄泉川先生
D-Don't come!
来るな　近づいたら
If you come any closer, I'll kill her!
殺すぞう
Don't worry about me, just arrest the suspect!
私には構わず　犯人を
What do we do?
どうします
Shut up!
黙れ！
Let me use that for a second.
ちょっと貸せ
Right...
はい
I really will kill her!
本当にやっじまうぞ
I'm doing great!
絶好調
How immature.
なんとはしたない
Oh, but it's amazing she got the high score!
へ　ハイスコアなんてすごいじゃないですか
なかなかやりますね
You've done quite well,
but I'm not going to lose!
でも　負けませんよ
Geez.
たっく
That happened because you got too
relaxed after the hostages were saved.
人質を救出したからって
気を抜くからあんなことになるじゃん
But you didn't have to hit me...
だからって私まで
I did it!
やった　スコア更新
You beat my high score?!
Saten-san, amazing!
佐天さん　すごい
It's almost time for school curfew.
そろそろ　完全下校時刻だな
That's right.
そうですね
Now go on!
ほら　行ってこい
You're supposed to redeem yourself with hard work, remember?
失敗は仕事で取り返すじゃん
R-Right...
は　はい
I'll be serious this time!
次は本気で行くからね
Oh like you weren't serious last time?
先のが本気じゃなかったと
Out of all the things you do, please don't kick it.
間違っても蹴らないでくださいな
Oh, really? I didn't know you could do that.
その手があったか
No cheating, okay?
だめですよ　ずるしちゃ
U-Um... Hey, you girls!
あ　貴方達
うん？
Huh?
It's going to be school curfew time soon.
もうすぐ完全下校時刻ですよ
Please head home now.
早くお家に帰りなさい
Huh?
あれ
Could you be...
もしかして
あ～　あの時の
From that time...
Thank you for that time.
その節はお世話になりました
Oh, thank you for saving us...
こっちこそ助けてもらちゃって
Um, did you lose some weight?
あの　少し痩せました
Actually, you look really worn down.
というよりやつれたような
Oh, do I?
え　そう
Maybe you should take better care of your skin.
お肌ももう少しお手入れされたほうがよろしいかと
Anti-Skill job must be hard.
<Antiskill>
警备员も大変なんですね
It is...
そうなのよ
So then,
どうです　そのストレス
How about you relieve some stress with this?
これにぶつけてみませんか
But, I'm working now, so...
でも仕事中だし
It might be good for your skin, too.
お肌にもいいかもしれませんよ
Maybe I could give it a try—
や　やってみようかな
Ouch!
あっ　いてっ
Don't let them intimidate you!
乗せられてどうする
Now you girls, go home!
ほら　お前らは　帰った帰った
It's the scary teacher from that time...
あの時の怖い先生
Now you too!
ほら　そっちも
It's school curfew time already!
もう完全下校時刻じゃん
Go home!
帰った帰った
Huh?
あれ
It's Kounoeda.
鴻野江だ
Someone you know?
知り合い
He's a classmate.
クラスメートです
そんなに親しくはないんですけど
Although we don't know him very well...
He's one of those people who are hard to get close to.
ちょっと近づき難い感じだもんね
Phew...
It's so hot!
あっちちち
Oh it stings!
浸みる
What's wrong, Tessou?
どうした　鉄装
Oh it's stinging the part I scraped...
いいや　擦り剥いたところに浸みて
Not that...
そうじゃなくて
You've been acting a bit strange lately.
最近ちょっと変じゃん　お前
Even today, you arrived late, you became a hostage, you're getting intimidated by students...
今日だって　遅刻するわ　人質に取られるわ
学生に乗せられるわ
Yes...
I can't really say you were the best Anti-Skill before this,
<antiskill>
もともとできのいい 警备员とは言えなかったけど
but haven't you gotten a bit lax lately?
弛んでるじゃないか
I'm sorry...
すみません
Anyhow, a nice bath after a full day's work is the best!
何やともあれ　一日の仕事終えて浴びる風呂は　最高だな
Yes it is.
そうですね
Don't you think so, Komoe-sensei?
子萌先生もそう思うじゃん
Sir, a Sunagimo please!
叔父さん　砂肝です
Right away.
You're drinking great as usual!
相変わらずいい飲みっぷりですね
Tessou Tsuzuri!
鉄装綴里
叔父さん　にちょうあだいをください
Y-Yes...?
あ　はい
Your weak point is your weak heart!
いいか
お前の弱点は弱気の虫だ
はいよ
あ　あと　やきいもです
...And your boobs, too!
胸張っていけ
I see...
はいよ
は
Hit it hard!
ガツンと勝つじゃん
All right?
ガツンと
That's right.
そうですよ　ガツンガツンですよ
Slam it down hard, all right?
I've had enough!
あ～　私はもう
Sir, Liver-steak please!
叔父さん　手羽てきです
はいよ
Right away.
Phew...
Hit it hard, eh?
ガツン　か
I have to work hard...
頑張らなきゃ
Today we are going to patrol Areas A to B.
今日の巡回はエリアAからD
We will split up and go.
手分けして行くじゃん
All right, Tessou?
いいな　鉄装
Yes!
はい
Um...
えっと　こっちが北だから
Since north is this way...
Where did you get separated from your mommy?
ママとはどこで逸れたのかな
Phew...
は～　うまく行かないな
It never work out like I want it to...
Huh?
That kid...
あの子
All right.
良し
You there, it's going to be school curfew time soon.
君　もうすぐ完全下校時刻ですよ
Head home now.
早くお家に帰りなさい
Um... You...
あの　君
Oh, it's Gekishou 9!
激賞９
How nostalgic...
懐かしい
I didn't know they had older games like this in Academy City...
こんな古いゲームが学園都市にあったなんて
I used to play it a lot when I was younger.
昔よくやったな
And 10 never came out...
結局１０は出なかったんだよね
Oh, that wasn't my point!
じゃなくて　君は早くお家に
You need to head home already!
Hey you!
君
Phew...
Sir, Pork Legs please.
叔父さん　てびちです
Right away.
はいよ
Also Banh Xeo and raw bamboo shoots please!
<Bánh-Xèo>
後　焙煎と筍のお刺身です
Hey Tessou.
なあ　鉄装
Yes?
え　はい
If something's worrying you, tell me.
悩みがあるなら聞いてやる
言ってみるじゃん
Oh, is it something about love?
お～　コイバナですか
It's not like I have anything worrying me...
別に悩みなんて
Then why are you making so many needless mistakes?
じゃあ　何であんなへまばかりするじゃ
I'm sorry.
すいません
That's right.
そうですよ　「命短し恋せよ乙女」ですからね
They say: life is short. Make love, maidens!
Oh, Tessou.
そうだ　鉄装　お前趣味はあるか
Do you have a hobby?
Hmm?
え？
Well, it doesn't have to be a hobby,
いや　趣味じゃなくてもいい
偶には　何か好きなことやってみれじゃん
but do something you like once in a while.
Something I like...
好きなこと？
Summer changes women into hunters.
夏は女を狩人に変えるんです
It's all about lifting your spirits!
気晴らしじゃん
Anything is fine; just have a lot of fun.
なんでもいい
羽目を外して　パアットさあ
A lot of fun...
パアット
That's right...
そうですね
Right.
はい
Okay.
よし
Sir, Water Bug please!
叔父さん　めんたです
Right away.
はいよ
Erm... Komoe-sensei...
あの　子萌先生
It's been bothering me but...
前から気になってたんですけど
なんですか
Oh what is it?
What kind of place is this, actually?
Tsuzuri
during
Summer
Vacation
A Certain Scientific Railgun
暑假琐事
ここ　なんの屋台なんです
You're going to be late again?
また遅刻だとう
What in the world are you doing?
一体何やってんじゃん
Well...
それが　一学期の評定を纏められてなくて
I haven't finished preparing the grades for the first trimester...
Huh?!
はぁ～　そんなの夏休み前に終わらせとくもんじゃんよ
That stuff is supposed to be finished before summer vacation.
すいません
I'm sorry...
Geez, fine then...
たっく　しょうがないな
Teacher's Lounge
You don't have to work today.
今日はもう来なくていいじゃん
Huh?
However, finish all of that today.
その代り今日中に終わらせるじゃん
Right!
はい
And also, our next drinking party... you're paying.
それから　次の飲み会はお前持ちじゃん
Right!
はい
え？
What?!
I'm finished!
終わった
Oh, it's this late already.
もうこんな時間
Something I like, hmm...
好きなこと　か
You're trying too hard for the big attacks.
大技狙いすぎでしょう
Also, you should separate your offensive and defensive moves a bit more.
後行使のメリハリをちゃんとつけた方がいいよ
It's better to not attack at all than to do half-baked attacks.
中途半端な攻撃なら　やらないほうがましだもん
You are...
あんた
I used to really be into this.
昔嵌ってたんだ
Will you let me play for a second?
ちょっと替わってくれる
Huh?
Did you know...
知ってる
if you press the start button down longer...
スタートボタン長押しすると
And also if...
それで　後は
ほら　来い
A hidden character?
隠しキャラ
That's right.
そう　その割には全然使えないんだけどね
However, he's absolutely useless in spite of all that.
How do you know all that?
何でこんなことを
Don't you like this?
好きなんでしょう　これ
Don't you want to know all the secret tricks in games you like?
好きなゲームの裏技って　知っときたいでしょう
And this boy is kinda cute.
それに　この子　ちょっと可愛いし
Nope. Not at all...
いや　全然
What?!
Is this all right?
<Antiskill>
いいの　警备员のくせに
You're supposed to be Anti-Skill.
I have the day off.
今日はお休み
Since my school work is done,
学校の仕事も終わったし
I thought I'd have a little fun for once.
久しぶりに羽を伸ばしてみようかなぁって
I see.
Now then,
さーて　腕は鈍ってないかな
have I maintained my skills?
Oh Komoe-sensei...
お　子萌先生
Yes...
はい
え　黄泉川先生が緊急事態
What?
Yomikawa-sensei has an emergency?!
Erm yes...
え　はい　でも
But...
Yomikawa-sensei is...
黄泉川先生が
But...
けど
Yet...
でも
Jamie!
Jamie
I'm sorry. Please play this!
ごめん　これやっといて
Huh?
Oh, the Jamie End is really exciting!
Jamieエンドすっごい熱いから　絶対見てねー
Make sure you watch it!
Yomikawa-sensei!
黄泉川先生
I can't drink any more.
もう飲めないじゃん
And this was the emergency?
緊急事態ってこれですか
Absolutely.
これですよ
Why did you start drinking so early?
なんてこんな時間から
How much did you drink?
一体どれだけ飲んだですか
At least five or six bottles between the two of us.
二人で軽く５、６升です
Tessou-sensei, isn't this fun?
鉄装先生　楽しいですか
Of course not.
楽しいわけないじゃないですか
Then, how was your day today?
じゃ　今日はどんな一日でした
Huh?
え？
How was it yesterday?
昨日は
Or the day before that?
その前はどうです
Well...
いや　別段楽しくはなかったかな
It wasn't especially fun, if you ask me...
Since I'm busy with my job.
仕事が忙しかったですし
I think everyday is fun,
私は毎日が楽しいですよ
since there are a lot of students in this city.
この町には　いろんな生徒がいますからね
Huh?
Right...
えい
There are some troublesome students who blow away the roof at my house though.
中には　私の家の屋根を吹き飛ばす困ったちゃんもいますけど
Oh?
Your roof?
え？　屋根をですか
That's right.
はいです
But...
でも　私はそんな子も含めて　生徒が大好きなんですよ
I love students, including ones like that.
Is it like that for you, Tessou-sensei?
鉄装先生はどうですか
All right!
よし
Today, we have Areas I to L.
今日はエリアIからLだな
Let's split up and—
手分けして
I'll start patrolling from Area L.
じゃあ　私はエリアLから回りますね
You're really excited today.
ずいぶん張り切ってるじゃん
Wait up!
待って
You there!
ちょっと貴方　どこのアガシオンなの
Where are you going?
H-Hey!
ちょっ　ちょっと
What school are you a student at?
貴方どこの生徒さん
I'm not a student!
生徒じゃないんだよ
シスターなんだよ
I'm a sister!
So, the doughnut you dropped was swept away by the cleaning robot.
それで　落したドーナツを清掃ロボットに回収されたと
Touma told me, that this country has a
great law called the "Three Second Rule".
この国には３秒ルールという偉大な決まりことがあるって当麻は言ってたんだよ
I don't think that rule applies to roads.
道路がルールの適用外だと思うけど
Oh, hey!
は～　こら　私のドーナツ帰して
Give me back my doughnut!
Hey...
Erm...
えっと
Eh... dear guest?
あの　お客様
All of it.
全部
Everything?
全部？
Everything.
全部
I see.
なるほど
That girl says she wants to buy all the hamburgers in this shop and won't listen to what anybody else says?
あの子が店のハンバーガを全部買い取ると言って譲らないと
ねー　貴方どこの生徒さん
Hey...
What school are you a student at?
Kirigaoka Girl's Academy.
桐ヶ丘女学院
But I'm freelance right now.
でも今はフリー
Freelance?
フリー
So, why do you need so many hamburgers?
で　何で　ハンバーガがそんなにいるのかしら
It's an unforgettable taste.
忘れられない味　だから全部
That's why I want them all.
Erm...
えっと
It's too much for me...
やっぱり私には
Oh no, I shouldn't feel weak!
いや　だめだめ　弱気になちゃ
I should go on to the next thing!
次々
Huh?
What's the matter?
どうしたの
I dropped my pendant... I guess
ペンダント落とした　かな
Pendant?
ペンダント　どんなやつ
What does it look like?
It has a photo in it.
写真がはいてるの
Ah, a locket.
あ～　ロケットね
A locket?
ロケット？
That's what we call pendants that can have photos inside them.
写真を入れられるペンダントはそういうでしょう
What?
うそ　今の子言わないの
Kids nowadays don't call it that?
Pendant...
ペンダント
Right...
そう　そうだった
You dropped it around here?
えっと　落したのはこの辺り
I think, maybe...?
そうかな
Then I'll help you look for it.
じゃあ　一緒に探したあげるね
It's nowhere.
ないなぁ
An earthquake!
じ　地震
Hey was that an earthquake just now?
ね　今の地震
Oh, was it shaking?
へ　振れた　気のせいじゃない
It must have just been you.
Oh was it?
そうかな
I found it.
あったの
I see.
そう　良かったね
I'm glad.
I'm glad, too.
良かったなの
Oh yes, what school are you a student of...
そういえば　貴方どこの学校の　って
H-Hey...
I can't even find a single locket...
ロケット一つ見つけた上げられないなんて
Am I really trying hard enough?
私頑張ってるのかなぁ
She's really late.
遅いですね
What is she doing?
何やってるじゃん
What? A Jamie user!
へ　jamie使い
I can't lose this!
これは負けられないって
You're really good!
なかなかやるわね
A clothesline!
乗りアッと
All right!
よし　私だって「大宮Jemie」と呼ばれてたんだから
They used to call me Omiya Jamie, you know!
Hooray!
やった　いい分
It's even now!
I'm gonna win this match for sure!
この勝負必ず取る
I can do it!
行ける
This is the end!
これで終わりよ
So my skills went down...
やっば　腕鈍ったか
But, it was really exciting for a moment.
でも 久々に燃えたな
Omiya Jamie, eh?
大宮Jemieね
Eh?
You were listening?
いやだ　聞こえて
Oh...
After that you played so much that you saw the Jamie End?
嘘　あの後本当にJemieエンド見るまでに遣りこんだの
No wonder...
道理で
Ah man, won't they ever release Gekishou 10?!
あ～～　激賞１０出ってないかな
They won't. It's a really old game.
出ないよ　あんな古いゲーム
If it does come out, I'll definitely win against you.
出たら　次こそ君に勝ってやるのに
Huh?
Nothing...
いや　楽しみにしてますよ
I'll be looking forward to it, Omiya Jamie-san.
大宮Jamieさん
Like I said, forget about that!
だからそれを忘れなさいって
Right here is fine.
ここまででいいよ
What are you saying?
何言ってるの　完全下校時刻過ぎてるんだから
It's past school curfew time, so I can't
leave middle schoolers all by themselves.
中学生だけじゃ
It's fine.
いいって
My home's right over there.
家もうそこだし
Oh, really...
そう
See ya.
じゃ
Oh...
あ　ありがとう
Thank you.
Huh?
Yes?
はい
What are you doing?!
何やってんじゃん　連絡も入れずに
You don't even contact me!
来ないなら来ないってちゃんと知らせるじゃん
Make sure to tell me if you're not coming!
After all, we'll get worried.
心配しちゃいますからね
It's not like that...
別にそういうわけじゃ
Anyway, I told you that you were supposed to pay today!
とにかく　言ったじゃん
今日はお前お持ちだって
—Sir, I'm going to jump hoops and have a hog's head today!
叔父さん
今日は思い切って値上がりです
You're not getting away with saying you forgot!
いや　忘れだとは言わせねえ
はいよ
Right away.
Like I said, hurry up and come!
だから　とっとと来るじゃん
はい
All right~!
He moved away?
転校した
Evidently so.
らしいですよ
That's really sudden to move away like that during summer vacation.
夏休みになんて　急ですよね
Oh really...
そうなんだ
Which school did he say he was transferring to?
何で言ったっけ　転校先の学校
Zassou Academy Middle School.
雑草学院中等部
What is Zassou Academy?
何　雑草学院って
There has to be a limit to how bad names can be.
ぞんざいな名前にもほどがあるでしょうに
Well, Zassou means "weed" in English.
雑草って　英語でweedじゃないですか
It's a school where the game producer Weed is its parent company.
ゲームメーカのweedが母体の学校なんですよ
Weed?
Weed
You know, the company that was once famous for a game called Gekishou.
ほら　昔激賞ってゲームで有名だったとこですよ
Oh, I might have heard about that before.
あ　なんか聞いて事あるそれ
Then, it's a school that trains game software creators?
じゃ　ゲームクリエータを養成する学校ってこと
It seems they only start with the professional stuff only in high school, though...
専門的なことは　高等部から見たいですけどね
But why Weed?
でも何でweedかな あんな落ち目な会社
They are in a decline.
そうですか
Oh really?
I have some favorite games from them.
あそこのゲーム結構好きなのありますよ　私
You're a maniac, Uiharu.
初春はファンだったもんね
I'm not like that.
You're acting strange.
私はそんなじゃ
何だ　気持ち悪いじゃん
Oh?
Oh, it's nothing.
いいえ　別に
Huh?
（わかったわかった）
You girls, go home when it's school curfew time, okay?
お前ら　完全下校時刻になったらちゃんと帰るじゃん
はい
Right!
All right!
よーし　頑張るぞう
I'll work hard!
What's with you?
行き成り　どうしたじゃん
Now let's go!
さあ　行きましょう
次はエリアEですね
It's Area E next, right?
Fじゃん
No it's F.
Oh was it?
あれ　そうでしたっけ
狙い定めた指先が指す
運命は絶望 それとも希望
ゆらぎの中で受信してゆく
悲しみにも負けない
勇気だけをください
大切なもの　守るため
「強さ」があると信じてる
Saving our future 一緒に
明日へのドア明けいた空へ飛び立とう
とある世界の果てで
駆け抜けてくReal Force
光を放って
Next Episode
If you're talking about jan, then it has to be jan ken.
TL Note: Jan, Ken, Pon is the Japanese version of Rock, Paper, Scissors.
—Sir, horse's mane please.
叔父さん　いものたべがみです
じゃんつーったら　じゃんけんじゃん
罗
汉
柏
园
Asunaro
Park
あと　マージャンじゃん
叔父さん　一文字のぐるぐるです
—Sir, twirls written in bold please.
And also Mahjong.
<Jean-Valjean>
あたしの前世は　ジャン‐バルジャン
叔父さん　豆腐の味噌つけです
And I was Jean Valjean in a former life!
—Sir, tofu dipped in miso please.
Jan round and round.
—Sir!
Jungle
叔父さん